Who wants to cook Aloo Gobi when you can bend a ball like Beckham?
Bend It Like Beckham is a comedy, drama, romance
film directed by Gurinder Chadha.
Jess Bhamra, the daughter of a strict Indian couple in London, is not
permitted to play organized soccer, even though she is 18.
When Jess is playing for fun one day, her impressive skills are seen by Jules
Paxton, who then convinces Jess to play for her semi-pro team.
Jess uses elaborate excuses to hide her matches from her family while
also dealing with her romantic feelings for her coach, Joe.
Jesminder 'Jess' Kaur Bhamra, played by Parminder Nagra.
Juliette 'Jules' Paxton, played by Keira Knightley.
Joe, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Mr. Bhamra, played by Anupam Kher.
Mrs. Bhamra, played by Shaheen Khan.
Pinky Bhamra, played by Archie Panjabi.
Bend It Like Beckham is a 2002 sports comedy-drama film directed by Gurinder Chadha
from a screenplay by Chadha, Paul Mayeda Berges, and Guljit Bindra.
The film stars Parminder Nagra, Keira Knightley, Jonathan Rhys Meyers, Anupam
Kher, Juliet Stevenson, Shaznay Lewis, and Archie Panjabi.
In Bend It Like Beckham, Jesminder Bhamra (Nagra) and Jules Paxton (Knightley)
chase careers in professional football despite their parents' wishes.
Development for the film began after Chadha, Bindra, and
Berges completed the screenplay by early 2001.
Nagra and Knightley were hired soon after, with casting rounded out with the
additions of Meyers, Kher, Stevenson, Lewis, and Panjabi by that May.
Principal photography began in June 2001 and lasted until September, with
filming locations including London, Shepperton Studios, and Hamburg.
Production collaborated with The Football Association, while the film's title refers
to David Beckham's curling free kick technique, also known as bending.
Bend It Like Beckham was theatrically released first in the
United Kingdom on 12 April 2002 by Helkon SK.
The film surprised critics, who praised the screenplay, light-hearted
tone, and commentary on Punjabi social norms and culture.
Bend It Like Beckham grossed $76.6 million at the box office.
In 2015 it was adapted into a stage musical that opened at the Phoenix Theatre.
The film explores themes of london, england, sports,
tradition, culture clash, immigration.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.